<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Macinthos | Passion Factory]]></title>
  <link href="http://passionfactory.github.com/blog/categories/macinthos/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://passionfactory.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-26T18:21:03+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://passionfactory.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Syaiful Bahri]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sharing a folder from your Mac to a virtual machine using VMware Fusion]]></title>
    <link href="http://passionfactory.github.com/blog/2013/01/18/sharing-a-folder-from-your-mac-to-a-virtual-machine/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-18T08:10:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://passionfactory.github.com/blog/2013/01/18/sharing-a-folder-from-your-mac-to-a-virtual-machine</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Note: VMware Tools must be installed for shared folders to work.</strong><!--more--></p>

<p><div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/fxNqdE7IanQ "></iframe></div></p>

<p><a href="http://kb.vmware.com/selfservice/microsites/search.do?language=en_US&amp;cmd=displayKC&amp;externalId=1004055">Source</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Make Eclipse Ide Support Retina Mac Display]]></title>
    <link href="http://passionfactory.github.com/blog/2013/01/15/how-to-make-eclipse-ide-support-retina-display/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-15T08:45:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://passionfactory.github.com/blog/2013/01/15/how-to-make-eclipse-ide-support-retina-display</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><blockquote><p>Got a retina display macbook pro, suddenly falling in love with the display, but seem my eclipse ide is not supporting the display which is 2880 x 1800 px.</p></blockquote></p>

<p>After doing some search on the web, there were a method to make eclipse ide adjust retina display.<!--more--></p>

<p>Just right click on Eclipse.app, then choose show package contents, then edit info.plist file on contents folder, then add this script below.</p>

<p><code>
&lt;key&gt;NSHighResolutionCapable&lt;/key&gt;
&lt;true/&gt;
</code></p>

<p>Copy your eclipse folder to another directory, then delete the original eclipse folder, than copy again eclipse folder on directory that you choose before, for example on your application directory to clear OS X's cache of the Info.plist.</p>

<p>Run eclipse ide as usual, and now you can enjoyed eclipse ide with retina diplay support.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gem Installing Problem Definitely GCC Missing Problem]]></title>
    <link href="http://passionfactory.github.com/blog/2012/12/16/gem-installing-problem-definitely-gcc-missing-problem/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-16T17:28:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://passionfactory.github.com/blog/2012/12/16/gem-installing-problem-definitely-gcc-missing-problem</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last day i have some problem with my harddrive. I can not boot into system after trying several way like repair the disk inside the OS and installer disc and also using <a href="http://www.alsoft.com/diskwarrior/">DiskWarrior</a>.</p>

<p>I'm kind of frustrated so i'm decide to save my files on the disk first using <a href="http://gparted.sourceforge.net/">GParted</a> live dvd method then doing fresh install for my system.<!--more--></p>

<p>Then the problem get around after updating my system to 10.8.2 version (Mountain Lion) when using gem install "something", i'm encounter error below.</p>

<p><code>
ERROR: Failed to build gem native extension.
…
make: /usr/bin/gcc-4.2: No such file or directory
</code></p>

<p>Yeah, apple definitely remove gcc on mountain lion. What should we do to fix this problem is installing missing gcc into system. I'm gonna use <a href="http://mxcl.github.com/homebrew/">brew package manager</a>, just simply install script like apt-get on Debian Linux distribution.</p>

<p><code>
brew install apple-gcc42
</code></p>

<p>Then fix the path</p>

<p><code>
sudo ln -s /usr/local/bin/gcc-4.2 /usr/bin/gcc-4.2
</code></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SSH File Transfer Protocol Android Menggunakan SSHDroid]]></title>
    <link href="http://passionfactory.github.com/blog/2012/12/06/secure-shell-access-android-using-ssh-droid/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-06T17:19:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://passionfactory.github.com/blog/2012/12/06/secure-shell-access-android-using-ssh-droid</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Jadi itu file-file .apk yang kepasang di file system (yang free dan legal tentunya ya) mau dibackup karena mau di reset.Sebenernya ada <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=jackpal.androidterm&amp;hl=en">terminal emulator</a>. Kalo hapenya udah di root bisa langsung mengakses directory .apk yang ada di directory data, lalu menyalin .apk yang ada ke sd card, kemudian untuk menyalin nya ke komputer selanjutnya tinggal menghubungkan hapenya dengan kabel data atau mengeluarkan sd card lalu memasangkan nya dengan card reader, report? yach saya merasakan nya juga.<!--more--></p>

<p><blockquote><p>Bagaimana kalo bisa langsung saja menyalin file .apk yang terpasang di direktori sistem android ke komputer?</p></blockquote></p>

<p>Unduh dulu SSHDroid <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=berserker.android.apps.sshdroid&amp;hl=en">di sini</a> jalankan SSHDroid, kemudian gunakan alamat IP yang tertera untuk menghubungkan sftp klien pada komputer dengan perangkat android</p>

<p><img src="/images/sshdroid.png"></p>

<p>saya menggunakan <a href="http://cyberduck.ch">Cyberduck</a> sebagai klien sftp yang saya gunakan pada komputer saya, gunakan root sebagai username dan password admin untuk memulai koneksi</p>

<p><img src="/images/cyberduck1.png"></p>

<p>file .apk yang akan saya salin berada pada direktori /data/app</p>

<p><img src="/images/cyberduck2.png"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Listening to - menampilkan notifikasi lagu yang sedang diputar itunes]]></title>
    <link href="http://passionfactory.github.com/blog/2012/11/30/listening-to-menampilkan-notifikasi-lagu-yang-sedang-diputar-pada-itunes/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-30T07:43:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://passionfactory.github.com/blog/2012/11/30/listening-to-menampilkan-notifikasi-lagu-yang-sedang-diputar-pada-itunes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.apple.com/itunes/download/">iTunes 11 emang keren</a>, biar tambah keren, instal <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/listening-to/id553010133?mt=12">Listening to</a> untuk menampilkan notifikasi lagu yang sedang diputar pada saat menjalankan iTunes.<!--more--></p>

<p>Harga aplikasinya kalo dirupiahin 19 ribuan, cukup worth buat yang ga mau ribet melakukan beberapa pengaturan seperti aplikasi gratis dengan fitur serupa <a href="http://osxdaily.com/2012/08/13/show-now-playing-itunes-alert-notification-center-mac-os-x/">ini</a> -_-. Setelah selesai diunduh dari mac app store, eksekusi aplikasinya kemudian gunakan menu notification setting, untuk mengatur pola notifikasinya.</p>

<p><img src="/images/b.png"></p>

<p><strong>Dan Ini Hasil Akhirnya</strong></p>

<p><img src="/images/c.png"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
